<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on Quality Tech Rider</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on Quality Tech Rider</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language></language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:21:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ToDoList</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/refer/todolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 13:21:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/refer/todolist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;E2E automation framework with integrations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UI automation - Java / Selenium	&lt;br&gt;
API automation - Rest Assured&lt;br&gt;
Performance automation - Gatling Java&lt;br&gt;
Burp suite - Security&lt;br&gt;
Usability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github - GitHub actions / Jenkins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fine-tuning-llms-and-vertex-ai--open-dource-ai-libraries&#34;&gt;Fine Tuning LLMS and Vertex AI , open dource AI Libraries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;any-innovation-concentrate&#34;&gt;Any innovation Concentrate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QuickLinksForReferences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/refer/quicklinksforreferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 23:45:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/refer/quicklinksforreferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gatling.io/reference/install/oss/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; &gt;https://docs.gatling.io/reference/install/oss/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important gatling commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-starting-recorder&#34;&gt;For starting recorder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mvnw.cmd gatling:recorder 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-running-the-gatling-simulations&#34;&gt;For Running the gatling simulations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mvnw.cmd gatling:test
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-the-simulation&#34;&gt;Running the Simulation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-the-following-command-to-run-your-specific-simulation-class&#34;&gt;Use the following command to run your specific simulation class:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mvnw.cmd gatling:test -Dgatling.simulationClass=MySimulation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;if-you-are-using-a-unix-based-system-linux-or-mac-you-would-use&#34;&gt;If you are using a Unix-based system (Linux or Mac), you would use:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./mvnw gatling:test -Dgatling.simulationClass=MySimulation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one of the famous personalities said , AI IS DANGEROUS , we need to agree to the fact that it is dangerous and fun too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danagerous aspect of it , everything which requires human brains are going to be replaced
Why it is fun ? it will be fun learning and understanding what it can do and how we can make use of it to make our lives comfortable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which Areas You can think , we can make use of AI ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1)Test Documentation - This is a repetitive and boring task
2)Automation Tools with AI Integration - You just need to know  how to communicate it to your model and get the code from it and use it
3)Code Reviews , Vulnerability Scans
4)Capturing all the webElements with meaningful Names from left to right using AI (Gives POM file in Java/Python or whichever language is requested)&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;Pain Point&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/refer/hugoreferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 23:45:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/refer/hugoreferences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a fast and flexible static site generator written in Go. It’s particularly useful for building websites and blogs. Here are some essential Hugo commands that can help you efficiently manage your Hugo projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installation
Before using Hugo commands, ensure Hugo is installed on your system. You can install it using a package manager or download it directly from the Hugo releases page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Commands
Create a New Site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo new site &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
This command initializes a new Hugo site in the specified directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a New Content File&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo new &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
For example, to create a new post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo new posts/my-first-post.md
Serve the Site Locally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo server
This command starts a local web server and watches for changes. The default address is http://localhost:1313.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build the Site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;test2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo
By default, this command generates the static site in the public directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuration Commands
Check Hugo Version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo version
This command prints the current version of Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generate Site with Specific Config File&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;config &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
This is useful if you have multiple configuration files and want to use a specific one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development Commands
List All Drafts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo list drafts
This command lists all draft content in your Hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enable Drafts, Future, and Expired Content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo server -D
The -D flag ensures that drafts, future, and expired content are included when serving the site locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear Cache&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;ignoreCache
This command tells Hugo to build the site without using the cache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deployment Commands
Specify Output Directory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo -d &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
For example, to generate the site in the dist directory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo -d dist
Minify Output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;minify
This command generates the site with minified output for faster load times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced Commands
Profile Build Performance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;templateMetrics &amp;ndash;templateMetricints
These flags provide detailed metrics on template rendering times, which can help optimize your site&amp;rsquo;s performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a Specific Theme&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo server -t &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
This command tells Hugo to use a specific theme when serving the site locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build for a Specific Environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;environment &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
For example, to build for a production environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo &amp;ndash;environment production
Help Commands
Get Help on a Specific Command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo help &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
For example, to get help on the new command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo help new
List All Available Commands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo help
Summary
These commands cover the essential functionality needed to create, develop, and deploy a Hugo site. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s flexibility and extensive command-line options make it a powerful tool for managing static websites. For more detailed information on each command, you can always refer to the Hugo documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gatling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/techblogs2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 22:07:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/techblogs2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HAR (Http Archive Resource)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of QA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/futureoftesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/futureoftesting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of software testing is being shaped by several emerging areas. Here&amp;rsquo;s a closer look at AI/ML Testing, Security Testing, and Performance Engineering and Load Testing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-aiml-testing&#34;&gt;1. AI/ML Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) are revolutionizing software testing by introducing automation and intelligent analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;test-automation&#34;&gt;Test Automation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can automate repetitive tasks, reducing the need for manual testing and increasing efficiency. AI-driven tools can generate test scripts, execute tests, and analyze results automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;intelligent-test-generation&#34;&gt;Intelligent Test Generation:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ML algorithms can analyze code changes and user behavior to predict the areas of an application most likely to contain defects, focusing testing efforts where they are needed most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-healing-tests&#34;&gt;Self-healing Tests:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can adapt to changes in the application UI, making test scripts more resilient to changes and reducing maintenance efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defect-prediction&#34;&gt;Defect Prediction:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can predict potential defects and prioritize testing based on historical data, reducing the time and effort required to identify issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-security-testing&#34;&gt;2. Security Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As cyber threats become more sophisticated, security testing is increasingly critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shift-Left Security: Integrating security testing early in the development lifecycle ensures vulnerabilities are identified and addressed sooner. This approach, known as &amp;ldquo;shift-left&amp;rdquo; testing, helps in building secure software from the ground up.
Continuous Security Testing: Implementing continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines with integrated security testing ensures that every code change is tested for security vulnerabilities.
Advanced Threat Simulation: Tools and techniques that simulate advanced threats can help identify vulnerabilities that traditional testing methods might miss.
AI in Security Testing: AI can be used to detect unusual patterns and behaviors that might indicate a security breach, helping to prevent attacks in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance Engineering and Load Testing
Ensuring software performs well under various conditions is crucial for user satisfaction and business success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shift-Left Performance Testing: Just like security, performance testing is moving earlier in the development cycle to catch issues sooner.
Continuous Performance Monitoring: Integrating performance testing into CI/CD pipelines allows for continuous monitoring and optimization of performance.
Scalability Testing: With the growing use of cloud services, testing for scalability to ensure applications can handle increasing loads without performance degradation is essential.
AI in Performance Testing: AI can analyze performance data to identify patterns and predict potential performance issues before they occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion-&#34;&gt;Conclusion :&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of software testing is being driven by advancements in AI/ML, increased focus on security, and the need for robust performance engineering. Adopting to these trends and learning the skills that are required would keep the testing jobs alive !&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gatling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/whatisgatling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/whatisgatling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gatling DSL (Domain-Specific Language) is a specialized programming language designed specifically for defining and running performance tests with Gatling, an open-source load testing tool. The DSL allows testers and developers to write expressive, concise, and readable performance test scenarios in Scala, which is the language Gatling is built on. The Gatling DSL abstracts much of the complexity involved in writing performance tests, making it easier to define scenarios, configure requests, and perform checks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Features of Gatling DSL are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-definition&#34;&gt;Scenario Definition:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define the sequence of HTTP requests and actions that simulate user behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;http-requests&#34;&gt;HTTP Requests:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configure GET, POST, PUT, DELETE, and other HTTP requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;checks&#34;&gt;Checks:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Validate responses with assertions, such as checking status codes, response times, and specific data in the responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;feeders&#34;&gt;Feeders:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide dynamic data to the tests using feeders, which can read data from CSV files, JSON files, and other sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;injection-profiles&#34;&gt;Injection Profiles:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Define how users are injected into the system over time, such as ramping up users gradually or starting with a burst of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reports&#34;&gt;Reports:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generate detailed and graphical reports of the test results, showing metrics like response times, request counts, and error rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example of Gatling DSL
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple example to demonstrate the usage of the Gatling DSL:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import io.gatling.core.Predef._
import io.gatling.http.Predef._

class MySimulation extends Simulation {

  // Define the HTTP protocol configuration
  val httpProtocol = http
	.baseUrl(&amp;quot;http://example.com&amp;quot;) // Base URL for all requests
	.acceptHeader(&amp;quot;application/json&amp;quot;) // Default headers
	.userAgentHeader(&amp;quot;Gatling&amp;quot;)

  // Define a feeder for dynamic data
  val feeder = csv(&amp;quot;data/users.csv&amp;quot;).circular

  // Define the scenario
  val scn = scenario(&amp;quot;My Scenario&amp;quot;)
	.feed(feeder) // Use the feeder for dynamic data
	.exec(http(&amp;quot;Get User&amp;quot;)
	  .get(&amp;quot;/user/${userId}&amp;quot;) // Dynamic URL based on feeder data
	  .check(status.is(200)) // Check that the response status is 200
	  .check(jsonPath(&amp;quot;$.name&amp;quot;).is(&amp;quot;${userName}&amp;quot;)) // Check the JSON response
	)

  // Set up the simulation with injection profile
  setUp(
	scn.inject(
	  atOnceUsers(10), // Inject 10 users at once
	  rampUsers(100).during(10.seconds) // Ramp up to 100 users over 10 seconds
	).protocols(httpProtocol) // Use the HTTP protocol configuration
  )
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation
HTTP Protocol Configuration: Sets the base URL and default headers for the HTTP requests.
Feeder: Reads dynamic data from a CSV file to be used in the requests.
Scenario Definition: Defines a scenario named &amp;ldquo;My Scenario&amp;rdquo; that performs a GET request to /user/${userId}, where ${userId} is a placeholder for dynamic data from the feeder. The scenario includes checks to validate the response status and specific data in the JSON response.
Injection Profile: Defines how users are injected into the simulation. In this example, 10 users are injected at once, and then 100 users are ramped up over 10 seconds.
Simulation Setup: Sets up the simulation with the defined scenario and HTTP protocol configuration.
Benefits of Gatling DSL
Readability: The DSL makes it easy to read and understand performance test scenarios, even for those who are not familiar with Scala.
Expressiveness: The DSL provides a rich set of features to express complex scenarios and checks concisely.
Reusability: Scenarios, feeders, and configurations can be reused across different tests, promoting code reuse and maintainability.
Extensibility: Custom actions and checks can be implemented in Scala, allowing for advanced customization and extension of the DSL.
The Gatling DSL is a powerful tool that simplifies the creation and management of performance tests, enabling teams to effectively simulate and analyze user behavior under load.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request Headers and Response Headers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/techblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/techblogs/techblogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-request-headers&#34;&gt;What are Request Headers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms additional meta-data sent by the client to server are called Request Headers , some of the main important request headers are as below .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1user-agent-&#34;&gt;1)User-Agent :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client identity such as browser name, browser version,OS version etc.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2connection-&#34;&gt;2)Connection :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the  State of connectivity between client and server , possibe values are {keep-alive;close}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3accept-----&#34;&gt;3)Accept     :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client prefernce format (eg .JSON,XML,HTML,XML,YAML etc) in which the server response to be sent to the client 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4accept-lang&#34;&gt;4)Accept-Lang:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client prefernce language (eg .EN-US,EN-IND,EN-GB etc) in which the server response to be sent to the client 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5content-type&#34;&gt;5)Content-Type:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the type of content/format (eg.json,xml,html,yaml) which client vis sending the request body/payload to the server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6authorization-&#34;&gt;6)Authorization :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the user auth details to the server to establish the client identity to the server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ok-now-lets-understand-what-are-response-headers&#34;&gt;Ok, Now lets understand What are Response Headers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms additional meta-data sent by the server to client are called Response Headers , some of the main important request headers are as below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1user-agent--1&#34;&gt;1)User-Agent :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client identity such as browser name, browser version,OS version etc.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2connection--1&#34;&gt;2)Connection :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the  State of connectivity between client and server , possibe values are {keep-alive;close}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3accept------1&#34;&gt;3)Accept     :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client prefernce format (eg .JSON,XML,HTML,XML,YAML etc) in which the server response to be sent to the client 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4accept-lang-1&#34;&gt;4)Accept-Lang:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the client prefernce language (eg .EN-US,EN-IND,EN-GB etc) in which the server response to be sent to the client 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5content-type-1&#34;&gt;5)Content-Type:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the type of content/format (eg.json,xml,html,yaml) which client vis sending the request body/payload to the server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6authorization--1&#34;&gt;6)Authorization :&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This header reveals the user auth details to the server to establish the client identity to the server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tricksandtips/tipsandtricksforgit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tricksandtips/tipsandtricksforgit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;this-is-just-a-sample-tricks-page&#34;&gt;This is just a sample tricks page&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>